Guide to the William Rose Benét Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Rose Benét Papers
1847-1957
1920-1950
YCAL MSS 1100
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
71.70
127 boxes + 4 broadside folders, 3 art, 1 cold storage
Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired primarily through gift of William Rose Benét, Marjorie Flack, and the estate of Marjorie Flack, 1948-1958.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 100 (cold storage): Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 131-133, 135: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
William Rose Benét (1886-1950)
William Rose Benét, born 2 February 1886 to James Walker Benét and Frances Rose (Neill) Benét, was an American poet, author, and editor who, along with his two siblings, Laura Benét and Stephen Vincent Benét, established the Benét family's literary reputation in the early through mid-twentieth century.
Benét was educated at Albany Academy before attending Yale College (1903-1907), where he served as editor of the Yale Courant and contributed to the Yale Record. After college, Benét went to work for Century Magazine as a reader. He served in the U.S. Air Services during the First World War, and after the war took work as a copy writer for an advertising firm. In 1920, Henry Seidel Canby brought Benét on as an assistant editor at the New York Evening Post. In 1923, Canby, Benét, and fellow editors Amy Loveman and Christopher Morley left the Post to form the Saturday Review, originally known as the Saturday Review of Literature.
Benét was the author of several collections of poetry, a novel, and a collection of essays. His autobiography in verse, The Dust Which Is God (1941), was awarded a Pulitzer Prize in 1942. In addition to his long-standing (1923-1950) position with the Saturday Review, Benét contributed to several compilations of English-language poetry and literature. Titles include The Oxford Anthology of American Literature and The Reader's Encyclopedia (1947).
Benét was married four times: first to Teresa Frances Thomson (1912-1919), with whom he had three children, then to the poet Elinor Wylie (1923-1928), to Lora Baxter (1932-1937), and lastly, to children's book author Majorie Flack (1941-1950).
Summary information is also available in the standard print and online biographical resources.
Scope and Contents
The William Rose Benét papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, printed material, and personal and family papers documenting the life and work of American author and editor William Rose Benét. The collection spans the years 1847 to 1957, with the bulk of the collection dating from roughly 1900 to 1950.
Collection material is chiefly in English; with some material in French, Italiana, Russian, and Hebrew.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1897-1955. II. Family Correspondence, 1883-1956. III. Writings, 1895-1957. IV. Printed Appearances of Writings by William Rose Benét, 1904-1950. V. Personal and Family Papers, 1847-1950.
Related Materials
Material by or relating to William Rose Benét acquired by the library from other Benét family sources can be located in the Benét Family Papers (YCAL MSS 1107). Material by or relating to William Rose Benét acquired by the library from non-family sources is located in the Benét Family Collection (YCAL MSS 1108). Additional material by or relating to William Rose Benét can also be found in the Stephen Vincent Benét and Rosemary Benét Papers (YCAL MSS 1046).
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Photographic prints; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Bacon, Leonard, 1887-1954; Benét, Rosemary, 1900-1962; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Berryman, John, 1914-1972; Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979; Cather, Willa, 1873-1947; Chubb, Thomas Caldecot, 1899-1972; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962; Dalven, Rae, 1904-; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970; Field, Sara Bard, 1882-1974; Flack, Marjorie, 1897-1958; Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; H. D. (Hilda Doolittle), 1886-1961; Harrold, Charles Frederick, 1897-1948; Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963; Ingalls, Jeremy, 1911-2000; Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964; Speyer, Leonora, 1872-1956; Teasdale, Sara, 1884-1933; Trausil, Hans, 1890-; Wharton, Edith, 1862-1937; Wood, Charles Erskine Scott, 1852-1944; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941; Wylie, Elinor, 1885-1928; Coudert Brothers; Yale University. Alumni
- Correspondence, 1897-1955; 1922-1950; Series I; 22.43; 50 boxes
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: General Correspondence, First Name Only, and Third Party Correspondence. General Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and chronologically within files. First Name Only is arranged alphabetically within letter general files. Third Party Correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Correspondence consists chiefly of single letters and small groups of incoming personal and professional correspondence to William Rose Benét and typescript carbons of Benét's outgoing letters to others. A significant amount of the General Correspondence in the series relates to Benét's editorial work on the Saturday Review (1923-1950) and other projects.
  There are letters from many English-language authors and literary critics of the first half of the twentieth century, as well as from friends, publishers, editors of journals and newspapers, literary and cultural organizations, and academic institutions. Larger files can be found for poets Leonard Bacon, Sara Bard Field (and her husband Charles Erskine Scott Wood), Jeremy Ingalls, and Leonora Speyer, the law firm of Coudert Brothers, Christopher and Helen Morley, Rae Dalven, and colleagues at the Saturday Review. Other correspondents include W. H. Auden, John Berryman, Elizabeth Bishop, Thomas Caldecot Chubb, E. E. Cummings, John Dos Passos, Robert Frost, H. D., Robinson Jeffers, Sinclair Lewis, Marianne Moore, Ezra Pound, and Sara Teasdale.
  A noteworthy component of the Correspondence series are letters to Benét's second wife, the poet Elinor Wylie. Correspondents include Willa Cather, Ford Maddox Ford, Charles Frederick Harrold, Aldous Huxley, Edith Sitwell, Hans Trausil, Edith Wharton, and Virginia Woolf. Files containing letters to Wylie exclusively are noted (to Elinor Wylie) in the folder description. The same descriptive strategy applies to the files containing letters to Marjorie Flack.
  The Third Party Correspondence subseries consists of the loose third party correspondence in the series. Most likely these letters came into Benét's possession as enclosures and, over time, were separated from the original letters.
  - General Correspondence
    - "A" general, 1927-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - A. and S. Lyons, Inc., 1947 January (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A. C. McClurg Co., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - A. S. Barnes Co., 1941–1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Abbott, Charles D. (Charles David), 1939–1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Abbott, Leonard D[alton?], 1949 December (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Abingdon-Cokesbury Press, 1950 January (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1946-1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Ackerman, Carl W. (Carl William), 1949 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ackerson, John, 1947–1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Adam and Charles Black (Firm), 1948 July (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - ADAM International Review, 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Adams, Frank P.; Adams, Esther, 1928-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Adams, Katharine, 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Adams, Leonie, 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Adams, Marguerite Janvin, 1947–1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Adventure, 1942–1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Agar, Herbert, 1929–1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Aiken, Conrad, 1933–1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Aikman, Duncan, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Albanese, Margaret, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Albany Academy, 1905-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Albatross Verlag, 1933 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Albright, Rachel, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Alden, John, 1947–1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Aldington, Richard, 1930 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Aldis, Mary, [?] August 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Alexander, Frances, 1949–1950 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1927-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Allen, Bernard M. (Bernard Melzar), 1946–1949 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Allen, Francis H. (Francis Henry), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Allen, Frederick Lewis, 1948 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Allen, Hervey, 1933–1948 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Alling, Kenneth Slade, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Alvarez del Vayo, Julio, 1942 December 7 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Alyea, Dorothy C. (Dorothy Collins), 1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1942–1954 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - American Bible Society, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - American Book Bindery, 1929 June 6 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - American Center of P.E.N., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1944–1948 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - American Council for Judaism, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - American Council on Education. American Youth Commission, 1942 May 7 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - American Field Service, 1942 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1944 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - The American Girl, 1942 June 4 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - American Jewish Congress. Women's Division, 1947 January 28 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - American Library Service, 1947–1948 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - American Printing House for the Blind (Louisville, Ky.), 1933 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - American Russian Institute, 1945 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - The American Scholar, 1937 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - American Veterans Committee, 1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Americans for Democratic Action, 1948-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 57-58)
    - Ames, Beatrice, 1948–1949 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Ames, Evelyn, 1948–1950 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Anderson, Marcia Lee, 1948–1950 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Anderson, Wallace L. [(Wallace Lowell)?], 1947 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Andrews, Benjamin R. (Benjamin Richard), 1949–1950 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Andrews, Leon Hudson, 1947; 1949 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Ann Watkins, Inc., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Ansley, Delight, 1948-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Anthony, Elizabeth, 1949–1950 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Antioch Press, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1946; 1950 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Argus Book Shop (Chicago, Ill.), 1933–1949 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Armour, Anobel, 1950 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Armour, Richard, 1949–1950 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Armstrong, Agnes, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Armstrong, Raymond P., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Arnold, Adelaid; Arnold, James Arthur, 1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Arnow, Harriette Louisa Simpson, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Artzybasheff, Boris, 1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Poster removed from Artzybasheff, Boris, 1950 (Box 114 (Oversize), Folder 3320)
    - Asbury, Edith Evans, 1950 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Asbury Park Press, 1950 January (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Ascoli, Max, 1949 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Asper, James E., 1947–1949 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Associated American Artists, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Aswell, Edward C., 1943–1948 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Atchley, Dana W. (Dana Winslow), 1941-1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Atherton, Gertrude Franklin Horn, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Athey, Mary, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Atkins, Elizabeth, undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1933-1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Aucourt, Joan, 1948–1949 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1944–1949 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Aufbau, 1946 May (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Auslander, Joseph, 1928–1942 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Austin, Alex, 1948–1949 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Austin, Warren Robinson, 1949 May 11 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Authors' Guild (U.S.), 1943-1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Authors' League of America, 1941 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Authors' Workshop for Veterans, 1946–1947 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - "B" general, 1907-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 98-104)
    - B. T. Batsford Ltd., 1949-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Babcock, R. W. (Robert Witbeck), 1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Babin, Victor, 1943 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Bacheller, Irving, 1945 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Bacon, Leonard, 1914–1946 (Box 3, Folder 109-110)
    - Bacon, Leonard, 1946-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 111-114)
    - Baer, Frank L., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Bailey, Margaret Emerson, [?] May 30 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Bain, Read (to Elinor Wylie), 1925 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Baker, Joseph B., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Baldry, Edith, 1927–1929 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Baldwin, Faith (to Elinor Wylie), [?] April 10 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Ballard, Juilet Brooke, 1943 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Bankhead, William B[rockman?], 1928 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Banta, Edward, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Barber, Florence H., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Barbour, Thomas, 1948 July 2 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Baring-Gould, William Stuart, 1947 January (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Barker, Eric W., 1946-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Barlow, Samuel L. M. (Samuel Latham Mitchell), 1949-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Barnard, Mary, 1949 January (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Barnard College, 1950 January (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Barnes, Lee Elwood, 1949 November (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Barnes, Nellie, 1925 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Barnes & Noble, 1948 July 16 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Barnouw, A[drian] J[acob], 1942–1943 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Barnum, Jay Hyde, 1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Barr, Isabel Harriss, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Barretto, Larry, 1929 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Barry, Philip; Barry, Ellen, 1932, undated (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Barrymore Theatre Corporation, 1950 April 6 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Bartholomew, Marshall, 1908-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Bartlett, Ruth Fitch, 1929, undated (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Baskin, Alice Haines, 1948–1949 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Bassetti, Fred, 1944 July 19 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Bates, Graham, Mrs., 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Bax, Clifford (to Elinor Wylie), [?] June 21 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Beach, [H. H. A., Mrs.?], 1933 November 23 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Beal, Gifford, 1947–1950 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Bean, Gladys Hyde, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Beaumont, Jane, 1947-1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Becker, Otto Matthew, 1947; 1949 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Beebe, William, 1949 November (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1950 January (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Bell, Arthur W., 1942, undated (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Bell, Doris, 1949–1950 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Bellamy, Ralph, 1943 December 10 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Benchley, Robert, 1943 December 5 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Benjamin Pollock Ltd., 1947–1948 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Bennett, Ethel Harper, 1931-1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Bennett, Isadora, 1949, undated (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Benson, Mary, 1928 December 28 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Bentley, Wilder, 1935; 1938 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Benton, Walter, 1942–1943 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Berdan, John M[ilton], 1929 February 27 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Bergh, Louis O. (Louis Otto), 1905 November 25 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Bernard Quaritch (Firm), 1927 November 23 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Bernays, Hella Freud, 1948 January 6 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Berninghaugen, D[avid?] K., 1943 July 30 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Berryman, John, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Bertram Rota Ltd., 1932 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Bettmann, Otto, 1944 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Bevington, Helen, 1947–1948 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Biberman, H. J. (Herbert J.), 1947 December 29 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Bickel, Mary, 1935 August 11 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Biddell, Francis, 1928–1949 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Bigelow, Dorothie, [?] December 17 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1930 May 2 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1946-1949, undated (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Bishop, Isabel, 1947-1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Bishop, John Peale; Bishop, Margaret, 1923-1948, undated (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Bishop, Morris, 1946–1948 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Björkman, Edwin, 1924–1925 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Black, John, 1948; 1950 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Blackwell, Betty, 1950 March 9 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Blackwell, Harriet Gray, 1948–1950 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Blanchard, Sarah E[liot?], [?] February 19 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Blanding, Henriette de S., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Blankner, Frederika, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Blish, James, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1946; 1948 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Bodenheim, Maxwell, 1947, undated (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Bogan, Louise, 1936 October 27 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Bohnhorst, Frank R. (Frank Runyan), 1941 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - The Bond Wheelwright Company, 1948-1951, undated (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Bone, David W. (David William), 1932–1939 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - Bonner, Amy, 1942-1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Bontemps, Arna, 1946–1950 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Book and Author War Bond Committee, 1944 April (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1941-1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Booker, Alma, 1948–1949 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Booth, Philip, 1949, undated (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Boss, George, 1948 April (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Boston Center for Adult Education, 1949 August 8 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Boston Universtity, 1949 July 29 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Bouche, Marian [Wright], [?] May 7 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - Bourinot, Arthur S[tanley], 1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Bowen, Catherine Drinker, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - Bowman (Firm), 1927 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 207)
    - Boynton, Ray, 1949 February (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - Brackett, Kate, 1947-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Bradbury, Bianca, 1946–1950 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Bradford, Mary Rose, 1947 May (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Bragin, Charles, 1942; 1944 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Braley, Berton, 1928, undated (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - Branch, Anna Hempstead, 1923-1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1929–1950 (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Braymer, Nan, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 216)
    - Breasted, Charles, 1933 June 14 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Breckinridge, Anne, 1944 April (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - Clipping removed from Breckinridge, Anne, 1944 April 15 (Box 114 (Oversize), Folder 3321)
    - Brennan, Joseph Payne, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Brentano, Lowell, 1946 October 22 (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - Brewer, Joseph, 1942-1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Brick Row Book Shop (New York, N.Y.), 1942 August 3 (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Brickell, Herschel, 1949–1950 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Brinkley, Maxine, 1942–1950 (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - Briscoe, Herman T., Mrs., undated (Box 6, Folder 225)
    - British Information Services, 1943–1944 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Brittain, Robert, 1946–1948 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Broadside, [1947?] (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Bromfield, Louis, 1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Brooklyn Public Library, 1944 December 27 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Brooks, Arthur J. H., 1943–1944 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Brooks, Gertrude V., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1943-1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 233)
    - Broughton, James, 1935–1949 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - Brown, Alice, 1933–1943 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Brown, E. K., 1943–1948 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    - Brown, Elinor Henry, 1949–1950 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    - Clipping removed from Brown, Elinor Henry, 1950 March 22 (Box 114 (Oversize), Folder 3322)
    - Brown, Ina Corinne, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    - Brown, John Mason, 1948–1950 (Box 6, Folder 239)
    - Brown, Robert Benaway, 1949–1950 (Box 6, Folder 240)
    - Brown, Rollo Walter, 1948, undated (Box 6, Folder 241)
    - Brownell, Amanda, 1940-1948, undated (Box 6, Folder 242)
    - Brownlee, Robert B., 1949 March 14 (Box 6, Folder 243)
    - Bruce Publishing Company, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    - Brumbaugh, Jesse F[ranklin?], 1950 January (Box 6, Folder 245)
    - Brumbaugh, Thomas B. [(Thomas Breadle)?], 1942–1948 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    - Bruncken, Herbert, 1936–1950 (Box 6, Folder 247)
    - Brush, Katharine, undated (Box 6, Folder 248)
    - Buchtenkirk, Elizabeth J., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    - Budenz, Lous F. (Louis Francis), 1944 (Box 6, Folder 250)
    - Buffalo Courier Express, 1942 August 11 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    - Buirgy, Mary, 1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - Bulosan, Carlos, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    - Bunker, John, 1929-1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 254-257)
    - Burden, Jean, 1947; 1949 (Box 7, Folder 258)
    - Burgess, Gelett, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 259)
    - Burlin, Helen, 1944; 1950 (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - Burns, Vincent Godfrey, 1944 April 12 (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - Burt, Maxwell Struthers, 1947–1950 (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - Burt, Nathaniel, 1949 July 29 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - Bush, Emily Henry, 1949-1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - Butler, Pierce, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Butts, Dorothy Worthington, 1935-1939, undated (Box 7, Folder 266)
    - Bye, George T., 1944; 1950 (Box 7, Folder 267)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1922-1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 268-269)
    - Byron, Gilbert, 1947-1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 270)
    - "C" general, 1909-1950, undated (Box 7, Folder 271-274)
    - "C" general, 1909-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 275)
    - C. A. Stonehil, Inc., 1949 December (Box 8, Folder 276)
    - Cabell, James Branch, 1920-1943, undated (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, [?] August 20 (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Cady, Harrison; Cady, Melina, 1942-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 279-280)
    - Printed material removed from Cady, Harrison, 1950, undated (Box 114 (Oversize), Folder 3323)
    - Cairns, Dolores, 1949–1950 (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - Caldecott, Alfred, 1928 May 7 (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - Caldwell, James Ralston, 1914-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 283-284)
    - Calverton, V. F. (Victor Francis), 1930 February 3 (Box 8, Folder 285)
    - Canadian Poetry Magazine, 1949-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 286)
    - Canby, Edward Tatnall, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel; Canby, Marion G., 1928-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Candee, Helen [Churchill?], [?] July 8 (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Candee, Marjorie Dent, 1946–1948 (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - Cane, Melville, 1934–1948 (Box 8, Folder 291)
    - Caperton, Helena Lefroy, 1942–1943 (Box 8, Folder 292)
    - Cardiff, Ira D. (Ira Detrich), 1949 October 24 (Box 8, Folder 293)